Guide to the Kurt Boone Photographs 2014-2015, 2017 PR 356
New-York Historical Society
Kurt Boone photographs
2014-2015, 2017
New-York Historical Society
Boone, Kurt B.
PR 356
1.5 Linear feet in two folders
This collection consists of 10 16x20 inch color photographs of subway performers taken by Kurt Boone mostly in 2015 in connection with his Subway Beats project, and two posters advertising a 2017 exhibition of his photos.
Biographical/Historical Note
Kurt Boone was born in Brooklyn, N.Y. in 1959. The New York City-based author, poet, and messenger is known for his work documenting street culture, including graffiti, urban cycling, street photography, skateboarding, subway busking, and spoken word performance.
Arrangement
The photographs are arranged in the container list alphabetically by title, with posters at the end of the list. Purchased photographs are in a separate folder from donated photographs.
Access Restrictions
Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
The photographs and posters in folder 1 were gifts of Kurt Boone in 2017. The photographs in folder 2 were purchases from the photographer in 2017 (Rosa Teresa) and 2018 (all others in folder 2).
Scope and Contents Note
This collection consists of ten 16x20" color photographs of subway performers taken by Kurt Boone mostly in 2015 (one was taken in 2014) as part of his "Subway Beats" project. In addition, there are two posters advertising a 2017 exhibition of Boone's photographs, Music in the Tunnels, held at Quimby's Bookstore in Williamsburg, Brooklyn.
The specific photographs in the collection are itemized in the container list below. Titles, dates and locations used in this finding aid are not found on the photographs themselves, but were provided by Kurt Boone in the collection's transactional documents.
Color photographs.; Street entertainers -- New York (State) -- New York.; Subway stations -- New York (State) -- New York
- Accordion Player, 2015 (Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Location: 42nd Street/6th Avenue
- Alice Tan Ridley, 2015 (Folder 2)
  Location: 42nd Street/Times Square
- Ebony Hillbillies, 2015 (Folder 2)
  Location: Times Square/42nd Street
- Jeff Masing (One Man Band), 2015 April 19 (Folder 1)
  Location: MTA Music Union Square/14th Street Station Stage
- Larry Wright & Sonia Wright, 2015 (Folder 2)
  Location: Union Square
- Maxidekalu, 2014 June 9 (Folder 1)
  Location: MTA Music Times Square/42nd Street Station Stage
- Mike Groisman, 2015 March 30 (Folder 1)
- Rosa Teresa, 2015 May 20 (Folder 2)
  Location: 23rd Street and 6th Avenue Station.
- The Silver Cowboy (Three Dancers in Paint), 2015 February 24 (Folder 1)
  Location: Times Square/42nd Street Station
- Trumpet Player (Artist Name Unknown), 2015 April 11 (Folder 1)
  Location: 59th Street and Lexington Avenue Station
- Poster for the Music in the Tunnels photo exhibition at Quimby's Bookstore in Brooklyn., 2017 (Folder 1)
  Poster features a photo of the Saw Lady, subway performer.
- Poster for the Music in the Tunnels photo exhibition at Quimby's Bookstore in Brooklyn, 2017 (Folder 1)
  Poster features a photo of Rosa Teresa, subway performer.